Welcome to Ludicrous Speed Postgres. I greatly appreciate the opportunity to educate you on Postgres performance and I'm glad that you decided to invest in yourself.
I'm going to be presenting the framework, the perspective, and the knowledge that I use in my own projects and for the clients that I work with.
However, as you're going through the course, I encourage you to modify or change up how I do things if it works better for you.
My most important metric is you learning and applying the information presented in this course to make your Postgres databases as fast as possible.
Basically, I want this course to make you a Postgres Performance Master, a wizard if you will, but it's going to require some work on your part, so please be sure to dedicate time to the lessons each week.
However, if you happen to fall behind, don't worry. Everything is recorded, even the live Q&As will be recorded, and you have access to the course for the next two years.
Lastly, I do want you to keep in mind that this is an entirely new course, and even though I've spent a fair amount of time on it, I'm sure you're going to find some rough spots or some things that are confusing to you.
So, I really want to hear your feedback so that I can make adjustments and make the course the best it can be, because I want to give every student the biggest wins possible.
And with that, let's go over each of the modules of the course.
So, the first module is Performance Fundamentals.
So, when you're thinking about performance, it's important to start with the right mindset, and here we're going to be talking about the conceptual framework and the thought processes that I use when I go out consulting on Postgres.
So, I think these really are fundamentals that will help you throughout the rest of the course.
The next module is Exploring B-Tree Indexes.
We're going to learn different techniques to get the most out of B-Tree indexes.
So, we cover things like multi-column indexes, partial indexes, expression indexes, as well as things like index-only scans and covering indexes.
So, all the different ways you can use the standard index type in order to get the most performance.
The third module is Optimizing Indexes.
So, here we're going to be covering things like vacuum, analyze, and the importance of statistics.
We also cover things like the importance of re-indexing, as well as removing unused indexes.
For the fourth module, we're going to be covering optimized data and index types, because the right data can lead to better performance.
So, we talk about the use of UUIDs, Booleans, arrays, and range types.
We also go into other index types other than B-Tree indexes, such as GIN, GIST, BRIN, and Hash.
The fifth module covers Text and JSONB Search.
So, large amounts of text and JSONB data can be challenging to store in the database, and we explore different ways that you can search through that data,
talking about full text search and fuzzy search, as well as different ways to target JSONB and which index types to use.
The sixth module, we're going to be covering advanced querying techniques.
These are things that you can use on occasion to get more performance, things like lateral joins, distinct on, CTEs, and even things like keyset pagination.
For module seven, we're going to be covering handling excessive data changes.
So, excessive data changing can really tank your performance.
So, we discuss how to handle large insert workloads or large update workloads, or even just how to do bulk loading.
And then the eighth module, we cover partitioning, aggregates, and beyond.
So, basically, eventually you're going to need to use different types of data handling solutions to handle your data, such as partitioning,
or maybe you need to use materialized views, or do summary tables or aggregate tables to give yourself the best performance out of Postgres.
So, that's basically the content in all eight modules.
So, I wanted to give you three pieces of guidance as you go through the course.
So, number one is complete each module and lesson.
Sometimes one lesson builds upon another, and particularly the performance fundamentals in the first module are going to be discussed at different points in every other module.
Number two is participate in the community.
So, the community is where different announcements are going to be made about the course.
For example, if maybe a time change needs to happen, it's also a place where you can give feedback about the course, or it's a place to ask for help or even converse with your fellow students.
And the third is to participate in the Q&As.
So, even if you don't have a particular question, even if you attend them, you can hear what other students are asking, and it's a great way to increase your knowledge in general,
because I actually don't know what questions may come up during the Q&As.
They may bring up questions that are outside of the course or something that they're working on themselves.
But those are my three areas of guidance I think you should focus on for the course.
Okay, now for some logistics.
Basically, these eight modules will be delivered over eight weeks.
Now, in terms of access to the community, a link will appear in this welcome lesson once it's ready.
And if you have any logistical problems working with the course or going through the lessons or things of that nature, you can contact support@rubytreesoftware.com.
And as I said, I definitely want this course to make you a Postgres Performance Master.
I know you may fall behind periodically, but I encourage you to try to get yourself caught up if you can, and reach out for assistance if you're stuck on something.